Personal Information

Address: 1599A 39th Street

Los Alamos, NM 87544

+1 (920) 858-8783 Phone: casey. alan. anders on @gmail.comEmail:

CASEY A. ANDERSON

https://www.linkedin.com/in/caseyalananderson

Work Information Address: P.O. Box 1663

Los Alamos, NM 87545

Phone: +1 (505) 667-5968 Fmailcasey_a@lanl.gov

Executive Summary

Nuclear engineer, physicist, and programmer with over six years of experience involving scientific computing, critical thinking, and analytical problem solving. Leader in student organizations, strong collaborator in diverse work environments, demonstrated history delivering products, and effective at communicating and publishing results.

"Put in a quote right here from someone, and its okay if it goes over a few lines thats okay" **Quote Person**

Professional Experience

Los Alamos National Laboratory

Los Alamos, New Mexico

Graduate Research Assistant Graduate Research Assistant Post Master's Research Assistant

NEN-5, Systems Design & Analysis¹ ISR-1, Space Science & Applications² W-13, Advanced Engineering Analysis³ XCP-3, Monte Carlo Codes⁴

May 2016 - Present Dec. 2016 - Present May 2011 - Jul. 2012 2010

Summer Intern

- Implemented new features in MCNP6 through writing code, developing benchmarks, publishing reports, and presenting the new features at various conferences [Pubs: ??,??,??]¹
- Gained significant knowledge and experience in the design, modeling, simulation, and analysis of a variety of radiation detectors for the Nuclear Detection Figure of Merit (NDFOM) project²
- Transitioned NDFOM from version 2.0 to 3.0 by modularizing and refactoring the backend Python code and through developing a cleaner, more intuiative HTML user interface for the customer²
- Managed the deployed server of NDFOM, including SQL database²
- Assisted in the development, testing, validation, and verification of the combined radiation transport and finite-element analysis multi-physics capability for the Engineering Campaign-7 Nuclear Survivability project3
- Developed unstructured mesh human phantoms for health physics applications with MCNP6 [Pub: ??]3
- Acquired DOE Q-level security clearance and Sigmas 1-10,11,12,13,15 and performed analysis on the W-88 system³
- Utilized the high performance computing (HPC) systems and utilities for advanced physics simulations and analysis^{1,2,3,4}
- Created a software visualization package for finite element geometries in MCNP simulations⁴

Medical College of Wisconsin

Milwaukee, Wisconsin

Graduate Research Assistant Department of Biophysics 2012-2016¹ Biophysics Representative, IT Liason Graduate Student Council 2014-2016²

- Funded my graduate studies through conducting the background research, providing the preliminary results, and co-authoring a successful R21 National Institute of Health (NIH) grant¹
- Patented a segmented reconstruction technique for artifact reduction in Magnetic Resonance Imaging [Pat: ??]
- Collaborated with a diverse group of professionals, including medical doctors and imaging technologists, to perform clinical research, meet deliverables, and submit the findings to various international conferences [Pubs: ??,??,??]
- · Interacted with clinical patients and subjects to collect patient data for clinical studies
- · Facilitated communication between students and staff in the graduate school with the university's Information Technology group²

University of Wisconsin - Madison

Madison, Wisconsin

Student Research Assistant Department of Medical Physics 2008-2011 **Chapter President** American Nuclear Society (ANS) 2010-2011

- · Researched methods for non-invasive quality assurance assessment of radioactive brachytherapy seeds
- · Managed the American Nuclear Society organizational duties, including activities such as recruiting guest speakers to present at meetings, organizing conference travel, and arranging public outreach events
- Mentored an taught a variety of students through volunteering at various events, such as Science Olympiad, middle and high school science fairs, and teaching local Boy Scout chapters to achieve their merit badges

Areas of Expertise

Physics/Engineering

- Nuclear Engineering
- Fourier Analysis
- Monte Carlo Methods
- Magnetic Resonance Imaging
- High Performance Computing
- Signal Processing
- Regularization Methods
- Radiation Detectors
- Multi-physics coupling
- Radioactive Material Handling
- O Computer Aided Engineering
- O Finite Element Analysis

Software

- MCNP
- Abaqus/CAE
- Linux
- Matplotlib
- Microsoft Office
- Matlab
- MacOS
- PostgreSQL
- Windows
- Vislt
- O RELAP

Programming

- Python
- Bash
- LATEX
- Unit Testing
- Matlab
- Mercurial
- Git
- Fortran
- Debugging
- Java

Other Skills

- Technical Writing
- Presentations
- Leadership
- Version Control
- File I/O
- Scripting
- Data Visualization
- Validation & Verification
- SQL Databases
- Clinical Work
- Server Management
- Animal Handling

Key (Skill Level)

• Expert • Intermediate ○ Beginner

Funding Sources

- General Electric / National Football League (GE/NFL) concussion study grant
- Department of Homeland Security (DHS) Department of Nuclear Detection Office (DND)
- DHS Nuclear Detection Figure-of-Merit (NDFOM)
- Engineering Campaign 7, Nuclear Survivability

Awards & Honors

SPOT Award Los Alamos National Laboratory August, 2017

Magna Cum Laude Abstract ISMRM 2016

Afilliations

- American Nuclear Society (ANS)
- · American Association of Physicists in Medicine (AAPM)
- International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine (ISMRM)

Education

Primary Education

M. Sc, Biophysics Medical College of Wisconsin April, 2016
M. Sc, Nuclear Engineering & Engineering Physics University of Wisconsin - Madison May, 2011
B. Sc, Nuclear Engineering University of Wisconsin - Madison May, 2011

Thesis: "Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping: Exploratory Development and Initiation of Processing Pipelines"

Additional Classes & Trainings

MCNP6 Intermediate Workshop Los Alamos New Mexico May, 2016 **CPR Certification Training** Milwaukee, Wisconsin May, 2015 **General Electric MR Programming Workshop** Madison, Wisconsin Oct, 2014 **Dale Carnegie Training** Los Alamos, New Mexico August, 2011 Introduction to Abaqus Minneapolis, Minnesota June, 2011 Introduction to Python Programming Los Alamos, New Mexico July, 2010 MCNP5 Beginner Workshop Los Alamos, New Mexico May, 2010